rescuethemes.com 2019-02-12

# Privacy Policy | Rescue Themes

We at Rescue Themes value your data privacy.  _We do not store credit cards.  We do not sell or rent your personal information to marketers or third parties._

Our website address is: https://rescuethemes.com.

Address

3420 Pump Rd. #304  
Richmond, VA 23233

email  
info@rescuethemes.com

## **What personal data we collect and why we collect it**

### **Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitors IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### **Where we send your data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Like most website operators, Rescue Themes collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Rescue Themes’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Rescue Themes’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Rescue Themes may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Rescue Themes also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on rescuethemes.com blogs/sites. Rescue Themes only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog/site where the comment was left.

We use Mailchimp for our email marketing and automation.

### **Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Rescue Themes’s websites choose to interact with Rescue Themes in ways that require Rescue Themes to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Rescue Themes gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up at [rescuethemes.com](http://focusedonfit.com/)to provide a username, email address, and other personal information. Those who engage in transactions with Rescue Themes are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Rescue Themes collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Rescue Themes . Rescue Themes does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### **Aggregated Statistics**

Rescue Themes may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Rescue Themes may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Rescue Themes does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### **Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Rescue Themes discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Rescue Themes’s behalf or to provide services available at Rescue Themes’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Rescue Themes’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Rescue Themes will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Rescue Themes discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Rescue Themes believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Rescue Themes, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Rescue Themes website and have supplied your email address, Rescue Themes may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Rescue Themes and our products. If you send us a request (for example via email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Rescue Themes takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### **Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Rescue Themes uses cookies to help Rescue Themes identify and track visitors, their usage of Rescue Themes website, and their website access preferences.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for 2 weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

Rescue Themes visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Rescue Themes’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Rescue Themes’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## **How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

We keep purchase history for a period of 7 years.

## **What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## **Business Transfers**

If Rescue Themes , or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Rescue Themes goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Rescue Themes may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

## **Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Rescue Themes may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Rescue Themes’s sole discretion. Rescue Themes encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a rescuethemes.com account, you might also receive an alert informing you of these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
